Janice Emily Bowers Notebooks, 1975-1994
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Janice Emily Bowers Notebooks, 1975-1994
MS 558
Bowers, Janice Emily.
This collection contains one box of field notebooks that documents Bowers' plant specimens in Arizona and northern Mexico, including a trip to the Rincon Mountains.
1.25 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/ E-Mail: LBRY-askspcoll@email.arizona.edu
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Acquired as gift of Janice Emily Bowers, 2014.
Biographical Note
These field notebooks belonged to Janice Emily Bowers, a botanist with the U.S. Geological Survey in Tucson, Arizona. The materials in this collection form the basis of two of her books, "The Mountains Next Door" and "A Full Life in a Small Place and Other Essays from a Desert Garden".
Arrangement
This collection is organized chronologically.
Scope and Content Note
Papers 1975-1994: The field notebooks of this collection measure 9.25 inches by 6 inches, with a few measuring 9.75 inches by 7.75 inches. Each contains entries for each plant specimen that was collected on the corresponding field visit. Also included are interspersed media clippings, home recipes, and other assorted information. The entries include both specimen lists and personal narrative.
Access Terms
Burgess, Tony L., 1949-
Turner, R.M. (Raymond M.)
Rincon Mountains (Ariz.)
Container List
- Field Notebook 560-1622, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Organ Pipe Field Notebook 560-1622, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Grand Canyon, Baja, Oak Creek Canyon, Punta Cirio, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Field Notebook 1623-1925, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Field Notebook 1927-2068, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Field Notebook 2069-2162, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Field Notebook 2163-2595, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Field Notebook 2596-2787, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Field Notebook 2788-2928, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Field Notebook 2929-2981, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Field Notebook 2982-2997, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Field Notebook 2998-3227, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Field Notebook 3228-3812, 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Field Notebook Rincons R1-R296, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Field Notebook Rincons R298-R547, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Field Notebook Rincons R548-R860, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Field Notebook Rincons R861-R1171, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Field Notebook Rincons R1172-R1409, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Field Notebook Rincons R1410-R1470, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)